在SunShine里
In Sunshine,
我们将使用ContentProvider来帮助我们高效地从互联网同步数据
we'll using content providers to help us
efficiently sync data from the Internet.
再加上Android框架里的一些辅助功能
Combined with utilities
in the Android framework.
它还简化了与用户界面交流数据库里的内容
It also simplifies getting database
content to and from our user interface.
我们通过继承一个ContentProvider类来实现一个新的类
We implement a content provider,
by extending the content provider class.
在SunShine里，我们叫这个类WeatherProvider
In Sunshine,
we'll call this class WeatherProvider.
我们将使用这个WeatherProvider来读写我们刚创建的数据库
We'll use the weatherprovider to read
and write the database we just created.
你大概已经急于开始创建这个WeatherProvider了
You're probably excited to get started
on building our weather provider, but
但是如果你仍不确定什么是ContentProvider
if you're still unsure about
what content providers are and
它们怎么工作的，我们做了一个非常棒的演练来演示
how they work, we've built a great
exercise that demonstrates how to take
如何利用这个趠級棒的东西
advantage of all this
gnarlishious goodness.
为什么说趠級棒呢？
Why gnarlishious?
因为这个演练充分利用了UserDictionary这个Provider
Because, this exercise leverages
the user dictionary provider.
所以如果你曾想让你自己的奇怪の詞匯
So, if you ever wanted to make your
radicaloutius vocabulariousness
被你的手機倗叐所理解当学习更多关于内容Provider的
understood by your mobile friendpanion
while learning more about content
看看下面的指示，有一个额外奖励的课程链接
providers, check the instructor notes
below, for a link to the bonus lesson.
创建一个内容Provider有几个步骤
Building a content provider,
involves several steps.
确定你的程序需要支持的URI
Determining the URIs your
application will need to support.
更新这个Contract使之包括这些URI
Updating the contract
to include these URIs,
填写一个URIMatcher，它支持所有这些URI
filling out a URIMatcher that
supports each of these URIs and
最后实现这六个需要的Content-Provider函数
implementing the six required
content-provider functions.
好了，现在的任务是确定URI。但是到底什么是URI？
Okay, the task is determining URIs,
but, what's a URI anyhow?
一个ContentProvider允许我们把数据和我们的View
A content provider allows us to think
of the data associated with our
联系起来通过统一资源标识符，也叫做URI。
views in terms of universal
resource identifiers or URIs.
URI的作用和它的名字表示的一样
URIs do exactly what their name implies.
它们标识一个资源。我们这里的情况是数据库里的一行数据
They identify a resource, in our
case a row, or rows, in a database.
你们几乎完全熟悉URI这个概念
You're almost certainly familiar
with the concept of a URI.
因为用作所有网页地址的URL实际上是URI的一种
Since the URL used for every web
address, is actually a type of URI.
网页这种情况，URI是被用来标识一个网页内容
In the case of the web,
it's a URI used to identify web content,
通过一个HTTP或者HTTPS格式
with an HTTP or HTTPS scheme.
在这个例子里，SunShine用URI来询问94043这个地点的天气信息
In this example, sunshine is using a URI
to query the weather for 94043 location.
我们的ContentProvider返回一个Cursor
Our content provider returns a cursor,
它包含这个URI所指的一行数据库里的数据
containing the database rows
that correspond to the URI.
通过改变这个URI询问的值
By changing the query value of the URI,
我们能让SunShine显示这个国家不同地方的天气
we can have Sunshine display weather
from different parts of the country.
每一个URI能包含这个Content格式
Each URI can contain the content scheme.
格式是URI的第一部分，在冒号前面
A scheme is the first part of a URI,
that precedes the colon, and
它指明这个URI将使用的协议
it identifies the protocol
that the URI will be using.
你们常看到像HTTP，FTP这样的格式在URI里
You are used to seeing schemes
such as HTTP and FTP in URIs.
“Content:”表示这个URI指向一个ContentProvider
Content colon implies that the URI
refers to a content provider.
中间这一段(Authority)，是一个唯一的字符串用来定位你的ContentProvider
A content authority, which is a unique
string used to locate your content
它应该几乎总是这个程序的包的名字
provider and it should almost always
be the package name of the application.
位置，通常指向程序里数据库的一个表
A location, which typically points to
a database table within the application.
最后是可选的Query，它既可以是URI路径的一部分，
And optional query, this query can
either be part of the URI path or
它也可以是传统URI加问号的形式
it can take the form of a traditional
URI query following a question mark.
根据目前情况，一个URI是数据的主要部分
As it turns out,
a URI is the primary piece of data,
它被传递进那些Intent。Ray已经非常好地描述过了。
that is passed in these intents that
Ray To so gloriously described.
在SunShine里，我们将充分利用这来打开详细信息界面
In Sunshine, we'll leverage
this to start the detail view,
伴随一个URI指向特定一天的天气信息
with a URI that points to the weather,
on a specific day.
详细信息界面，用这个URI来询问WeatherProvider
The detail view, uses this URI
to query weather provider and
并且获得正确的天气数据来显示
get the right weather data to display.
另外，这些ContentProvider URI也被用来
Another thing that these content
provider URIs, is used for
通知用户界面某个正显示
in android is to notify the user
interface that a piece of the data it is
的数据发送了改变
displaying has changed.
这个代码用到了Android里一个叫ContentObserver的东西
The code registers an Android
construct called a content observer,
来针对那个正在被显示的URI。
during our initial query,
against the URI that is being displayed.
当运行一个数据库更新程序时，通常是在另一个线程上。
When running a database update routine,
likely on another thread.
那个程序会告诉Android这个和这个URI相联接
That routine will tell Android that
the data associated with the URI
的数据改变了
has changed.
最终，这个URI应该重新读取数据库
And ultimately, that the URI
should requery the database, and
并且刷新显示内容
refresh the display.
这会引起界面刷新并且显示最新的数据
This will cause the display to refresh,
and show the latest data.
尽管你能看到这里，URI还没有改变
Even though as you can see here,
the URI hasn't changed.
内容Provider能提供各种排序的数据
Content providers,
can return all sorts of data.
但是Abstract的函数要么返回一个Cursor包含一个列表的物品
But the abstract functions return either
a cursor containing a list of items or
或一个单独的物品
a single item.
这些URIs怎么构建取决于不同的程序
How these URIs are structured
is up to each application.
但是Android也能帮助了把一个ID扩展成一个URI
But Android provides support, for
appending an ID to the URI path,
来指明程序想要的一个特定数据
to indicate that the application is
interested in a specific record,
而不是一个范围数据
rather than a range of records.
在Sunshine里，特定的日期时间
In Sunshine, the value for
a specific date and time,
被用来查询一个指定地址的天气
is appended to the query for
weather at a specific location.
这就需要返回一个指定的天气数据
And that causes a single
weather record to be returned.
所以，定义URIs
So, defining URIs.
来让我们的工作变得简单吧
To make it easy for
我已经定义了这些我们将要支持的数据URIs
us, I've defined these data
URIs that we'll be supporting.
有一些URIs
Some of these URIs,
存在是因为某个特定的数据需要在屏幕上被显示出来
exist because the UI has a view that
needs to expose that particular data.
例如被用来显示天气预报主菜单
Such as weather with location,
的天气和地址
which will be used to display
the main list of forecasts.
当然还有用来显示详细天气信息的
And of course,
weather with location and date.
具体地址和时间的天气
Which would be used to display
the detailed forecast information.
其他的URIs主要被用来写入数据库，插入、更新
Others, are used primarily for writing
the database, inserts, updates and
和删除
deletes.
这些基础的URIs对于测试也是有帮助的
Having these base URIs,
is also useful for testing.
现在是时候回到我们的WeatherContract了
Now it's time to go back
to our weather contract.
我们之前描述到什么是WeatherContract的时候
When we first described
what a weather contract is,
我们说过那是一个数据模型，储存和界面之前的一个协议
we said that it is an agreement between
the data models, storage and views.
Presentation描述那些信息时如何被访问的
Presentation describing how
information is accessed.
原来，除了通过数据库的列名称，
It turns out,
that in addition to the column names for
这些Contract也是可以被用来定义URIs的
our database, the contract is also
a great place to define the URIs,
我们的程序会用它们来访问数据
that our application will be
using to access its data.
下面，我们会解释你需要怎么构建你的WeatherContract
Next, we'll explain what you need
to add to your weather contract.
当你完全添加这段代码进你的程序后，
When you've completed adding
this code to your project,
我会来解释你做的是什么。
I'll explain a bit
about what you've done